### Curriculum Vitae of MD. MEHEDI HASAN



## Career Objective:

I am a progressive professional worker in the development sector with over 3 years of proven experience scholarly engaged with various projects in several organizations. In addition, I am holding a master's degree in Social Science with special concentration on Public Policy Analysis, NGO Management, Research Methodology, and Project Cycle Management. I am currently seeking NGO related jobs that will allow me to take challenges and apply my analytical, technical, capacity building, team building, and communications skills.

## Personal Information:

Address : Central Road First Drive, House – 111, Flat – 5B, Kolabagan, Dhaka-1205.

Cell : +880-1717-677451, +880-1521-252064

: mhshuvo29@gmail.com E-mail Nationality : Bangladeshi by Birth

Languages : Advanced Bangla, Fluent English and some understanding of Hindi.

Present Salary:	32,000	Expected Salary:	38,000
-----------------	--------	------------------	--------

# Education:

2012-2013 : Master of Social Sciences (M.S.S.), Public Administration, University of Dhaka. 2008-2012 : Bachelor of Social Sciences (B.S.S.), Public Administration, University of Dhaka.

## Work Experiences:

### February 01, 2018 to Present

: Officer (Project Support and Coordination) Position held

**Major Projects** Baseline survey of EMP preparation of Matarbari USCCF Power Plant Project

> Dhaka - CTG - Cox's Bazaar Railway Project Dhaka - Joydevpur - Ishwardy Railway Project

Environmental Master Plan Project (All over Bangladesh)

: Sustainable Research and Consultancy (SRC) Ltd. **Organization** 

To manage administrative, development, planning, and implementation policies,

procedures and programs in support of the project;

Maintain liaison with government/non-government authority, local & international

agencies and other stakeholders;

Support to prepare presentation, event report, organizing meeting/seminar, internal Succinct responsibilities

events, programs & field visit as and when necessary;

Conduct social/baseline surveys as and when required;

Assist in data collection, report preparation and further tasks as per instruction by

the authorized management.

# January 01, 2017 to January 31, 2018

Position held : Field Investigator

**Major Projects** Baseline survey of EMP preparation of Matarbari USCCF Power Plant Project

Third Urban Governance & Infrastructure Improvement Project (UGIIP-3)

Environmental Master Plan Project (All over Bangladesh)

Drainage Master Plan Project (16 Districts)

Organization : Sustainable Research and Consultancy (SRC) Ltd.

Collaborating with customers, claimants, policyholders & the local administration;

Field visit as and when necessary;

Organize and facilitate focus group discussion; Succinct responsibilities

Reviewing the investigation project thoroughly for detecting the possible loopholes

& reporting the results to the authorized person;

Draft accurate and concise reports & presentations based on all collected findings.

March 01, 2016 to September 30, 2016

Position held : Research Associate

**Organization** : Human Development Research Centre (HDRC)

#### Other Experiences & Voluntary Activities:

- Worked as a **Research Associate** (Part Time) of **Center for Asia-Pacific Initiative** (**CAPI**) for the period of 05.04.2019 to 05.08.2019 on the **Piloting Phase** of SME base Comparative Study in Developing Country
- Worked as a **Coordinator** in the Social Action Project "ইছেপূরণ (Icchepuron)" under the **Active Citizens Youth Leadership Training program** of British Council, supported by **Democracywatch**. <a href="http://www.dwatch-bd.org/ylp1.html">http://www.dwatch-bd.org/ylp1.html</a>
- Having experience of working as a 'Field Assistant' in the Third Urban Governance & Infrastructure Improvement Project (UGIIP-3).
- Conduct several field researches on Contemporary Local Government in Bangladesh, Politicization of Professionals, Migration Pattern in Dhaka city, and Corruption & Tadbir in Bureaucracy.
- Involved in organizing the festival entitled, "Bijoy-e Parbon-e" arranged by Utshe, marking 41st Victory Day of Bangladesh. http://www.thedailystar.net/news-detail-261174
- Founder member of the voluntary group "Friends Society of Rangpur" http://fsrbd.org/
- Voluntary regular **Blood Donor** (28th times till now).

# Training and Workshop:

- IT Diploma in "Enterprise Systems Analysis & Design with J2EE" from "Islamic Development Bank Bangladesh Islamic Solidarity Educational Wakf (IsDB-BISEW)". http://idb-bisew.org/
- Participant of the Active Citizens Youth Leadership Training Programme of British Council, supported by Democracywatch. <a href="https://www.britishcouncil.org/active-citizens">https://www.britishcouncil.org/active-citizens</a>
- Attended the Climate Culture and Art Symposium 2018 for Youth in Bangladesh under the Gobeshona Young Researcher's programme organized by ICCCAD. <a href="http://art-symposium-4youth.icccad.net/">http://art-symposium-4youth.icccad.net/</a>
- **Post-Graduate Diploma (PGD)** on Social Compliance and CSR Issues, organized by Institute of Apparel Research and Technology, (**BKMEA**). <a href="http://www.bkmea.com/training\_institite.html">http://www.bkmea.com/training\_institite.html</a>

# Distinctive Attributes:

- Profound knowledge on MS Word, MS Excel, PowerPoint, Web Applications, Social Media, HTML, CSS, Oracle/My SQL, Java etc.
- Typing Bangla with Bijoy software
- Flexible to travel frequently

- Ability to work under heavy pressure
- Enthusiastic to explore new places & cultures
- Adaptability with changes
- Well-disciplined & Punctual

# Distinction:

2005 : Got a board scholarship for achieving Golden A<sup>+</sup>.

## References:

Referee 1

Abu Jubayer, Director (Operation), Sustainable Research and Consultancy (SRC) Ltd. and Director (Operations), Contact for Systemachility, & Dayslemment, Stamford University, Paneladesh, Dhake

(Operations), Center for Sustainability & Development, Stamford University Bangladesh, Dhaka. **Cell:** +8801711-459532 **Email:** jubayer.buet.bd@gmail.com **Relation:** Professional

Referee 2 Md. Sultan Mahmud, Senior Sector Specialist (CEP, GJ&D, HRLS), BRAC, Baniachong, Habigonj.

Cell: +8801730-347653 Email: sultan.mahmud@brac.net Relation: Relative

**Referee 3** Farhana Ferdoush, Communication Officer, NIRAPOD-2 Project, Marie Stopes Bangladesh. Cell: +8801737-538962 Email: farhana.ferdoush@mariestopesbd.org Relation: Friend

### Acknowledgement:

I, the undersigned hereby certify that, to the best of my knowledge and belief, above mentioned credentials correctly describe myself, and I will be liable for any feigned information.

Md. Mehedi Hasan